#### RESEARCH INTERESTS

My main research interests lie in the intersection of **Machine Learning** (ML) and **Optimization**. Particularly, I am interested in developing systematic approaches to study facets, including robustness and interpretability, of ML models in real-world environments, where humans and high measurement uncertainties exist in the loop.

## **EDUCATION**

M.S. in Data Science

2021 - 2023 [expected]

Hanoi University of Science and Technology

• Engineer in Computer Science, GPA: 3.67/4.0, Major GPA: 3.88/4.0

2016 - 2021

Hanoi University of Science and Technology (HUST)

- Thesis: A Deep Reinforcement Learning based Online Charging Scheme for Target Coverage and Connectivity in WRSNs.

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

- **Ngoc Bui**, Duy Nguyen, and Viet Anh Nguyen. "Counterfactual Plans under Distributional Ambiguity" in *International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR)*, 2022.
- Tuan-Duy Hien Nguyen, **Ngoc Bui**, Duy Nguyen, Man-Chung Yue, and Viet Anh Nguyen. "Robust Bayesian Recourse," in *Conference on Uncertainty in Artificial Intelligence (UAI)*, 2022.
- **Ngoc Bui**, Phi Le Nguyen, Viet Anh Nguyen, and Phan Thuan Do. "A Deep Reinforcement Learning-based Adaptive Charging Policy for WRSNs," in IEEE *International Conference on Mobile Ad-Hoc and Smart Systems (MASS)*, 2022.
- Duy Nguyen, Ngoc Bui, and Viet Anh Nguyen. "Distributionally Robust Recourse Action," under review.
- **Ngoc Bui**, Duy Nguyen, Kim-Cuc Nguyen, Man-Chung Yue, and Viet Anh Nguyen. "Covariance-Robust Minimax Probability Machines for Algorithmic Recourse," under review.
- Duy Nguyen, Ngoc Bui, and Viet Anh Nguyen. "Feasible Recourse Plan via Diverse Interpolation," under review.

## **EXPERIENCES**

• Research Resident, VinAI Research

August 2021 - present

- Work under the supervision of Dr. Viet Anh Nguyen on robust and trustworthy ML, studying various paradigms of explanation methods for machine learning models and their robustness.
- Applied Rotation Project: Interactive Tool for 3D Point Cloud Segmentation.
- **Research Assistant**, Data Science Lab (HUST)

December 2019 - June 2020

- Study the Vietnamese address standardization problem that recognizes and normalizes free-form addresses into a common standard format.
- AI Research Intern, IBM Vietnam

*July 2019 - October 2019* 

- Apply PowerAI Vision to visual inspection problems in the car manufacturing process to detect dirt and dust defects in the car body after painting.

## **AWARDS & HONORS**

•	Honorable Mention in INFORMS Undergraduate Operations Research Prize	2022
•	Best Thesis Presentation Award.	2021
•	Winner in ASEAN-India Hackathon.	2021

• Third prize in Vietnam Olympiad in Informatics.

2016

2020

# **OPEN-SOURCE PROJECTS**

• **GeneticPython**, *pypi*: geneticpython

A simple and friendly Python framework for (multi-objective) genetic-based algorithms.

SCOSS, pypi: scoss
SCoSS (Source Code Similarity System) is an automatic system for determining the similarity of source codes focusing on

programming classes and competitive programming contests.

## **TEACHING**

• Applied Algorithms classes (outstanding service), *HUST* 2019 - 2021

Coaching high school students preparing for national olympiad contests in informatics.

2016 - 2017

# PROFESSIONAL SERVICES

• Reviewer at AISTATS 2022/2023.